Inventory of the Robert S. Norris collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Robert S. Norris collection
1898-2003
2008C9
Norris, Robert S. (Robert Stan)
90 manuscript boxes (36 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Collection relates to General Leslie R. Groves and the development of the atomic bomb, containing photocopies of government documents, correspondence, diaries, reports, memoranda, studies, and printed matter, microfilm, sound recordings, and transcripts of interviews. Used as research material for the book by R. S. Norris, Racing for the Bomb: General Leslie R. Groves, the Manhattan Project's Indispensable Man (South Royalton, Vt., 2002). Includes photocopies of documents released in response to Freedom of Information Act requests.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Access to audiovisual materials requires at least two weeks advance notice. Audiovisual materials include sound recordings, video recordings, and motion picture film. Hoover staff will determine whether use copies of the materials requested can be made available. Some materials may not be accessible even with advance notice. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives for further information.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2008.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Dr. Robert S. Norris is a senior research associate with Natural Resources Defense Council (NRDC) in Washington, D.C. His principal areas of expertise include all aspects of the nuclear weapons programs of the United States, Soviet Union/Russia, Britain, France, China, India, Pakistan, Israel and North Korea.
Dr. Norris received his Ph.D. in political science from New York University in 1976 and has taught at New York University; Miami University in Oxford, Ohio; Miami University's European campus in Luxembourg; and American University in Washington, D.C. He has been with the NRDC since 1984 and lives in Annapolis, Maryland.
Robert S. Norris NRDC web page, http://www.nrdc.org/nuclear/norris/norris.asp
Scope and Content of Collection
The files were used as research material by Robert S. Norris in the writing of Racing for the Bomb: General Leslie R. Groves, the Manhattan's Project's Indispensable Man, a biography of General Leslie R. Groves, published by Steerforth Press in 2002.
The files also contain material about the Manhattan Project and related matters. The files consist of mostly Xerox copies of files from the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA), the Library of Congress (LOC), Truman Presidential Library, Hoover Presidential Library, The Bancroft Library, Office of History, U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, Hagley Library, West Point Special Collections, and the Los Alamos archives. A great deal of material comes from Record Group 77, U.S. Army Corps of Engineers Manhattan Engineer District (MED) files and from RG 200, the Personal Papers of General Leslie R. Groves. Two useful NARA microfilm collections from RG 77 are included, the Harrison-Bundy Files (9 rolls) and "Top Secret" correspondence of special interest to General Groves (5 rolls).
The collection is organized into series, retaining the donor's folder titles and arrangement of supporting materials for the book chapters and related research files.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into series, retaining the donor's folder titles and arrangement of supporting materials for the book chapters and related research files.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Groves, Leslie R., 1896-1970.; Atomic bomb.; Nuclear weapons.; World War, 1939-1945--United States.; World War, 1939-1945--Japan.; United States. Army. Corps of Engineers.
Collection Contents
- Racing for the Bomb: General Leslie R. Groves, the Manhattan's Project's Indispensable Man Supporting materials.
  Arranged by book chapter
  - Introduction, Chapters 1, 2, 3, 4 (Box 65-67.)
  - For My Grandchildren and drafts (Box 65-67.)
  - Chapter 5, Military Engineering, Leslie R. Groves Letters from Europe (Box 33-35.)
  - Chapter 6, Vermont records, Nicaragua (Box 33-35.)
  - Chapter 7, DC, Fort Peck (Box 33-35.)
  - Chapter 8, Leavenworth, Army War College (Box 33-35.)
  - Chapter 9, Construction Corps letters (Box 33-35.)
    - Leslie R. Groves Comments on Fine and Remington (Box 33-35.)
    - Fine and Remington interviews (Box 88-90.)
    - Japanese Internment (Box 88-90.)
    - Pentagon (Box 88-90.)
  - Chapter 10, NAS Reports (Box 88-90.)
  - Chapter 11, Silver program (Box 88-90.)
  - Chapter 11, Hanford, Oak Ridge (Box 41-43.)
    - Contractors (Box 41-43.)
    - Silver Program (Box 41-43.)
    - Holston (Box 41-43.)
  - Chapter 12 (Box 44-46.)
    - Los Alamos National Lab archive A-84-019 documents (Box 44-46.)
  - Chapters 13 and 14 (Box 54-56.)
    - Moe Berg, Files from Record Group (RG) 226, RG 77 from Jeff Richelson, Azusa, Ramona (Box 54-56.)
  - Chapter 14 (Box 36-38.)
    - Alsos (Box 36-38.)
    - Intelligence, Foreign (Box 36-38.)
    - French Problem (Box 36-38.)
    - German Bomb (Box 36-38.)
    - Boris Pash (Box 36-38.)
    - London Liaison Office, Alsos (Box 36-38.)
    - Oranienberg (Box 36-38.)
    - Farm Hall, Peppermint (Box 36-38.)
    - Vemork (Box 36-38.)
    - Dahlem Bombing (Box 36-38.)
    - Samuel Goudsmit material (Box 39-40.)
  - Chapter 16 (Box 47-49.)
    - Combined Development Trust (Box 47-49.)
    - Boris Pregel (Box 47-49.)
    - Truman Committee (Box 47-49.)
    - Combined Policy Committee (Box 47-49.)
    - Diplomatic History of the Manhattan Project and Combined Development Trust (CDT) meetings (Box 47-49.)
    - International Control, Ore (Box 47-49.)
    - Groves Banking and CDT (Box 47-49.)
    - US Canada Cooperation (Box 47-49.)
    - Paul Guarin (Box 47-49.)
  - Chapters 17 and 18 (Box 47-49.)
  - Chapters 19-20 (Box 68-70.)
    - Camel (Box 68-70.)
    - Special Table- Codes (Box 68-70.)
    - Indianapolis (Box 68-70.)
    - Shipping Schedules (Box 68-70.)
    - Tinian Cables (Box 68-70.)
    - History of Project A, Ramsey (Box 68-70.)
    - Orders and Cables (Box 68-70.)
    - Casualties and Effects (Box 68-70.)
    - Duplicates (Box 68-70.)
    - Interim Committee (Box 68-70.)
    - Hiroshima (Box 68-70.)
    - Third Bomb (Box 68-70.)
    - Target Committee (Box 68-70.)
    - Farrell and Propaganda (Box 68-70.)
    - Leaflets (Box 68-70.)
    - Silverplate and B-29s (Box 68-70.)
    - Norman Ramsey (Box 68-70.)
    - Nagasaki (Box 68-70.)
    - 1st Technical Services Detachment (Box 68-70.)
    - Fat Man (Box 68-70.)
    - "Always the Target" (Box 68-70.)
    - 509th CG (Box 68-70.)
    - Little Boy (Box 68-70.)
    - Oppenheimer (Box 85-87.)
    - Oppenheimer/Leslie R. Groves letters (Box 85-87.)
    - Oppenheimer Bio (Box 85-87.)
    - Jumbo (Box 85-87.)
    - Trinity (Box 85-87.)
    - Trinity articles (Box 85-87.)
    - Trinity Seismology (Box 85-87.)
    - Bainbridge Material (Box 85-87.)
    - Blinding Proposal, July 17, 1945 (Box 85-87.)
    - Kirkpatrick memos (Box 85-87.)
    - Wendover (Box 85-87.)
    - Leslie R. Groves, Postwar Comments on Use (Box 85-87.)
  - Chapter 21 (Box 74-76.)
    - Public Relations, W. Laurence (Box 74-76.)
    - Crossroads, Los Alamos National Lab (Box 74-76.)
    - Blakeslee (Box 74-76.)
    - Public Relation, Censorship (Box 74-76.)
    - Manhattan Engineer District (MED) Public Relations Programs (Box 74-76.)
    - Truman Announcement (Box 74-76.)
    - Japanese Cyclotrons (Box 74-76.)
    - Smyth Report (Box 74-76.)
    - Atomic Diary, John Moynahan (Box 74-76.)
    - Visit to Hiroshima, September 1945 (Box 74-76.)
    - Japanese A-bomb (Box 74-76.)
  - Chapter 23 (Box 21-23.)
    - International Control (Box 21-23.)
    - Leslie R. Groves on the Army of the Future (Box 21-23.)
    - Acheson, Lilienthal (Box 21-23.)
    - International Control (Box 21-23.)
    - Joe-1 (Box 21-23.)
    - Ziegler (Box 21-23.)
    - Long-range detection (Box 21-23.)
    - Russia and the bomb Leslie R. Groves assessment (Box 21-23.)
    - Russia (Box 21-23.)
    - Declassification, Tolman Leslie R. Groves, UN, Hancock, Record Group 59 (Box 21-23.)
    - Stimson to Franklin Delano Roosevelt on International Control (Box 21-23.)
    - Central Intelligence Group (CIG), National Intelligence Authority (NIA) (Box 21-23.)
    - Office of Special Projects (Box 21-23.)
    - Tolman, Post-war planning (Box 21-23.)
    - Bush, Conant on International Control, September 1944 (Box 21-23.)
    - JCS (Joint Chiefs of Staff) (Box 21-23.)
  - Chapter 24 (Box 71-73.)
    - Sandia Pioneers (Box 71-73.)
    - Armed Forces Special Weapons Project (AFSWP) documents (Box 71-73.)
    - AFSWP Histories (Box 71-73.)
    - Manhattan Engineer District (MED) Transition, 1946 (Box 71-73.)
    - UK Bases, 1946 (Box 71-73.)
    - Military Liaison Committee (Box 71-73.)
    - Sandia Histories (Box 71-73.)
    - Articles on dropping Bomb (Box 71-73.)
    - Truman material (Box 71-73.)
  - Chapter 25 (Box 82-84.)
    - Oppenheimer security case 1954 (Box 82-84.)
    - Leslie R. Groves in Strauss Papers, Hoover Library (Box 82-84.)
    - Wallace (Box 82-84.)
    - Remington Rand (Box 82-84.)
    - Espionage, Chapter 25 (Box 82-84.)
    - Leslie R. Groves, Ike Hiroshima (Box 82-84.)
    - Groves Political Views (Box 82-84.)
    - Promotion Difficulties (Box 82-84.)
    - General, Chapter 25, 1948-1961 (Box 82-84.)
  - Chapter 26 (Box 82-84.)
    - Leslie R. Groves comments on Vincent Jones History (Box 82-84.)
    - Leslie R. Groves Comments on book by Michel Rouze on Oppienheimer (Box 82-84.)
    - Leslie R. Groves Comments on Stimson article (Box 82-84.)
    - Uranium to USSR, Maj Jordan's diary (Box 82-84.)
    - Leslie R. Groves on Feis (Box 82-84.)
    - Dzau, 1969 (Box 82-84.)
    - Distaff (Box 82-84.)
    - MIT affair, 1970 (Box 82-84.)
    - Now It Can Be Told (Box 82-84.)
    - Advanced Off Gas (AOG) (Box 82-84.)
    - Bust at West Point (Box 82-84.)
- Leslie R. Groves Collected Materials
  Contains appointment books, unpublished material by his son Richard, two volumes of letters from his father, and correspondence with other family members
  - Groves Diary, 1940-1943 (Box 80-81)
    Daily appointment books kept by Groves' secretary
  - Groves Diary, 1944-1948 (Box 30-32)
  - James C. Marshall Diary, 1942 (Box 80-81)
  - Col. F. T. Matthias Diary, 1943 (Box 53)
  - Papers of Chaplain Leslie Richard Groves, 2 volumes (Box 51)
  - Leslie R. Groves Personal Letters (Box 53)
  - Larmee Collection, Letters (Box 52)
  - Unpublished material on Leslie R. Groves by his son, Richard H. Groves
    - Blooding the Regiment (Box 50)
    - Taming the Dragon, Parts 1 and 2 (Box 50)
    - Off to Cuba with the Regulars (Box 50)
    - Wars Stories, Jump Stories and Other Lies and Half-Truths, Volume 1, Parts A and B (Box 52)
- Research Files: General
  - Military Bios from Assembly/Corps of Engineers Office of History (CEHO) (Box 62-64.)
  - Manhattan Engineer District (MED) Org Charts and rosters (Box 12-14)
  - Leadership and Management (Box 12-14)
  - Administrative Style (Box 12-14)
  - Military Policy Committee, minutes (Box 12-14)
  - Leslie R. Groves
    - Memos to General Marshall, "Atomic Fission Bombs" (Box 12-14)
    - Personal Style (Box 12-14)
    - Personal (Box 12-14)
    - Banking (Box 12-14)
    - Biographical (Box 12-14)
    - Staff (Box 12-14)
    - Orders (Box 12-14)
    - Decorations (Box 12-14)
    - Medical (Box 12-14)
    - Press Clippings (Box 12-14)
    - Biographical (Box 12-14)
    - Memos to File (Box 12-14)
    - Richard (Box 12-14)
    - Gwen (Box 12-14)
    - Articles (Box 12-14)
  - Record Group 200 Papers, Leslie R. Groves unfiled (Box 12-14)
  - Groves, Leslie R. 201 File (725 pages) (Box 59-61)
  - Correspondence, Sandia Pioneers (Box 59-61)
  - Interview Transcripts and Notes (Box 59-61)
  - Groves FBI File (Box 59-61)
  - Finding Aids, Record Keeping (Box 18-20)
  - Oral History Finding Aids (Box 18-20)
  - Larmee, Letters (Box 18-20)
  - Heisenberg (Box 18-20)
  - FOIA Successes (Box 18-20)
  - Enola Gay Exhibit (Box 18-20)
  - Manhattan District History, Guide (Box 18-20)
  - Los Alamos National Lab Docs (Box 18-20)
  - Groves Letter log, 1962-1970 (Box 18-20)
  - Leslie R. Groves copy of selected pages from Henry L. Stimson diaries (Box 18-20)
- Research Files: Biographical files
  Collected materials on scientists, political and military figures. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Alvarez, Luis (Box 7-9.)
  - Arneson, Gordon, Memoirs, Oral History (Box 7-9.)
  - Ashbridge, Whitney (Box 7-9.)
  - Bacher, Robert, Los Alamos National Lab Interview, 1980 (Box 7-9.)
  - Baruch, Bernard Papers (Box 7-9.)
  - Bethe, Hans, Oppenheimer Correspondence (Box 7-9.)
  - Bethe, Los Alamos National Lab Interview, 1979 (Box 7-9.)
  - Bohr, Niels (Box 7-9.)
  - Bridgman, P.W. (Box 7-9.)
  - Brobeck, William (Box 7-9.)
  - Bundy, Harvey (Box 7-9.)
  - Bush, Vannevar (Box 7-9.)
  - Compton, Arthur (Box 7-9.)
  - Conant, James (Box 7-9.)
  - Creedon, Frank (Box 7-9.)
  - DeSilva, Peer (Box 7-9.)
  - Farrell, Thomas F. (Box 7-9.)
  - Fermi, Enrico (Box 7-9.)
  - Feynman, Richard, Los Alamos National Lab Interview, 1979 (Box 7-9.)
  - Furur, Adm Julius A. (Box 7-9.)
  - Graves, Ernie "Pot" (Box 7-9.)
  - Hadden, Gavin (Box 7-9.)
  - Harrison, George L. (Box 7-9.)
  - Hayward, Adm John "Chick" (Box 7-9.)
  - Keith, Percival "Dobie" (Box 7-9.)
  - Kirkpatrick, Elmer (Box 7-9.)
  - Lavender, Capt. Robert (Box 7-9.)
  - Lawrence, E.O. (Box 7-9.)
  - McMahon Brien (Box 7-9.)
  - Marshall, George C. (Box 62-64.)
  - Marshall, James C. (Box 62-64.)
  - Matthias, Franklin (Box 62-64.)
  - Morrison, Phillip, Los Alamos National Lab interview, 1979 (Box 62-64.)
  - Nichols, Kenneth D. (Box 62-64.)
  - Nier, Alfred, Reminiscences (Box 62-64.)
  - O'Leary, Jean (Box 62-64.)
  - Oliphant (Box 62-64.)
  - Oppenheimer, Frank (Box 62-64.)
  - Parsons, Deak (Box 62-64.)
  - Roosevelt, F.D. (Box 62-64.)
  - Sengier, Edgar (Box 62-64.)
  - Serber, Robert, Los Alamos National Lab interview, 1979 (Box 62-64.)
  - Slotin (Box 62-64.)
  - Somervell, Brehon (Box 62-64.)
  - Styer, Wilhelm (Box 62-64.)
  - Szilard, Leo (Box 62-64.)
  - Teller, Edward (Box 62-64.)
  - Tolman, Richard (Box 62-64.)
  - Tyler, G.R. (Box 62-64.)
  - Urey, Harold (Box 62-64.)
  - Warren, Stafford (Box 62-64.)
  - Weinberg/Wigner (Box 62-64.)
  - Weisskopf, Victor (Box 62-64.)
  - Wheeler, John (Box 62-64.)
  - Wilson, Robert (Box 62-64.)
- Research Files: Collected Documents
  Collected material from libraries and archives, including Finding Aids to various Record Groups and collections
  - Strauss Papers, Hoover Library (Box 24-26)
  - Lawrence Papers, Bancroft Library (Box 24-26)
  - Teller Interview, at Los Alamos National Lab, 1993 (Box 24-26)
  - Harrison, Bundy Index: Record Group (RG) 77, 9 rolls A1108 (Box 24-26)
  - Harrison Bundy files, RG 77 (Box 24-26)
  - "Top Secret" National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) A1109 (Box 24-26)
  - Hagley Documents (Box 24-26)
  - Harrison Bundy (RG 77) 9 rolls NARA microfilm 1108 (Box 1-2)
  - "Top Secret" (RG 77) 5 rolls NARA microfilm 1109 (Box 1-2)
  - Sage Sentinel, 12-31-43 to 02-09-45 and Let's All HEW to the Line, 07-09-43 to 07-23-43 (1 roll microfilm) (Box 1-2)
  - RG 200 Papers of Leslie R. Groves Finding Aid (Box 1-2)
  - RG 77 Manhattan Engineer District (MED) Finding Aid (Box 1-2)
  - RG 227 Office of Scientific Research and Development (OSRD) Finding Aid (Box 1-2)
  - RG 374 Armed Forces Special Weapons Project (AFSWP) Finding Aid (Box 1-2)
  - RG 326 Atomic Energy Commission (AEC) Finding Aid (Box 1-2)
  - RG 326 AEC, AtlantaRecord Center 4NN-326-8503 Finding Aid (Box 1-2)
  - RG 160 Army Service Forces Finding Aid (Box 1-2)
  - RG 226 Office of Strategic Services (OSS) Finding Aid (Box 1-2)
  - Research collections, Libraries, Archives (Box 1-2)
  - Office of History, US Army Corps of Engineers (Box 1-2)
  - Los Alamos National Lab Finding Aids (Box 1-2)
  - Pre-Manhattan documents, 1940-1942 (Box 10-11)
  - Briggs, Breit, OSRD (Box 10-11)
- Research Files: Interviews by others
  Post-war material in the form of interviews, speeches, and his commentary on writings about the Manhattan Project
  - Early Atomic Energy Commission Legislation (Box 27-29)
  - Domestic Policy (Box 27-29)
  - Atomic Energy Commission General (Box 27-29)
  - Scientists Movement (Box 27-29)
  - Crossroads (Box 27-29)
  - Los Alamos National Lab Bradbury, Postwar (Box 27-29)
  - Condon (Box 27-29)
  - Groves, Human Experiments (Box 27-29)
  - Groves on Hewlett and Anderson: The New World (Box 27-29)
  - Post-war Bombing Studies (Box 27-29)
  - Scientists, Biographies (Box 27-29)
  - Groves, Oral Interviews (Box 77-79)
  - Eagles interview, May 8, 1962 (Box 77-79)
  - Joint Committee on Atomic Energy (JCAE), February 24, 1948 (Box 77-79)
  - JCAE, February 4, 1950 (Box 77-79)
  - Patch interview, September 11, 1945 (Box 77-79)
  - Groves, Oral History (Box 77-79)
  - Raymond Henle, August 9, 1968 (Box 77-79)
  - Leslie R. Groves, The Military Engineer article, June, 1946 (Box 77-79)
  - Interview, Carroll, June 15, 1949 (Box 77-79)
  - Groves, Interviews, Freed (Box 77-79)
  - Groves, Interviews (Box 77-79)
  - Hailey Interview, December 11, 1957 (Box 77-79)
  - Fort Belvoir Conference, September 23-26, 1946 (Box 77-79)
  - Leslie R. Groves, Articles (Box 77-79)
  - Magazine Articles, 1945-1947 (Box 77-79)
  - Groves, Magazine Articles (Box 77-79)
  - Speeches, Awards, 1945 (Box 77-79)
  - Speeches, Awards, 1946 (Box 77-79)
  - Leslie R. Groves Speeches, 1947-1952 (Box 57-58)
  - Leslie R. Groves Speeches, 1956-1965 (Box 57-58)
  - Groves, Radio and TV (Box 57-58)
  - Newspaper Clips, 1948-1950 (Box 57-58)
  - Groves, Comments on Newspaper Articles (Box 57-58)
  - Groves, Comments on Books, Articles, 1950s-1960s (Box 57-58)
  - Leslie R. Groves, Comments on Gowing (Box 57-58)
  - MGM Film, Beginning or the End, 1946 (Box 57-58)
  - Leslie R. Groves on Film (Box 57-58)
  - Declassified FBI CINRAD files -"Communist Infiltration of the Radiation Laboratory" (Box 15-17)
  - Declassified FBI CINRAD Files -"Communist Infiltration of the Radiation Laboratory" (Box 3-6)
- Research Files: Interview Cassettes (Box 59-61)
  Conducted by Robert S. Norris, Stanley Goldberg, and others. Arranged alphabetically
  - Interviews with Robert S. Norris
    - Barnes, William, January 28, 1998 (Box 59-61)
    - Camm, Lt. Gen. Frank A. (USA, retired), February 16, 1998 (Box 59-61)
    - Cooper, Lt. Gen. Kenneth (USA, retired), November 24, 1997 (Box 59-61)
    - Cushman, Lt. Gen. John H. (USA, retired), January 9, 1998 (Box 59-61)
    - Derry, John, February 10, 1999 (Box 59-61)
    - Furman, Robert F., March 28, 1998 (Box 59-61)
    - Graves, Lt Gen Ernest (USA, retired), December 29, 1997 (Box 59-61)
    - Irving, James, February 28, 1998 (Box 59-61)
    - Marks, Anne Wilson, October 24, 2000 (Box 59-61)
    - Owen, Patricia Cox, April 11, 1998 (Box 59-61)
    - Volpe, Joseph, June 13, 2001 (Box 59-61)
    - Watson, Coni O'Leary, April 4, 1998 (Box 59-61)
  - Interviews with Stanley Goldberg (Box 59-61)
    - Bainbridge, Ken T., February 13, 1990 (Box 59-61)
    - Campbell, Patsy, June 23, 1993 (Box 59-61)
    - Chorpening, Claude, Maj. Gen. (USA, retired), August 21, 1992 (Box 59-61)
    - Derry, John, November 20, 1991 (Box 59-61)
    - Furman, Robert, February 10, 1990 (Box 59-61)
    - Lansdale, John, February 7, 1990 (Box 59-61)
    - Lansdale, John, March 19, 1991 (Box 59-61)
    - Larmee, Charlotte, August 14, 1991 (Box 59-61)
    - Marks, Anne Wilson, September 24, 1991 (Box 59-61)
    - Martin, Gerry Elliot, August 30, 1991 (Box 59-61)
    - McGowan, Louise Jackson, July 23, 1991 (Box 59-61)
    - Morrison, Philip, February 12, 1989 (Box 59-61)
    - Mountain, Thomas, August 6, 1991 (Box 59-61)
    - Pash, Boris, April 18, 1990 (Box 59-61)
    - Rhodes, Fred B., September 17, 1991 (Box 59-61)
    - Robinson, Alan, May 2, 1991 (Box 59-61)
    - Robinson, Gwen Groves, May 3, 1991 (Box 59-61)
    - Rotblat, Joseph, July 9, 1993 (Box 59-61)
    - Schurcliff, William S., July 13, 1989 (Box 59-61)
    - Seaborg, Glenn, April 17, 1990 (Box 59-61)
    - Volpe, Joseph, September 6, 1991 (Box 59-61)
    - Watson, Coni O'Leary, February 9, 1989 (Box 59-61)
  - Interviews with others (Box 59-61)
    - Haight, Gilbert, 1990 (Box 59-61)
    - Havens, William, September 2, 1988 (Box 59-61)
    - Morrison, Philip, January 9, 1990 (Box 59-61)
    - Teller, Edward, June 7, 1993 (Box 59-61)
    - Weisskopf, Victor, January 12, 1990 (Box 59-61)